what is the problem or train to fix well
one thing is those current systems the
interface of those current systems with
each other and the net effect are
unsustainable and unsustainable means
self terminating means that these
systems run to their own end and then
fall off some kind of cliff right until
when we look at growth curves of
different kinds of organisms anytime we
see a growth curve that has an
exponential up that is not forever
and sometimes the exponential up goes
logistic and that's very nice sometimes
it drops off pretty hard before it
logistics sometimes it goes through a
lot of unstability sometimes just
Exponential's up and then drops off a
cliff right so we were under half a
billion population for all of human
history as far as we know until the
Industrial Revolution and then in just
over two hundred years we went up to
over seven billion people and growing
and that is a profound exponential
population curve not only have we went
through this profound exponential
population curve in relationship to our
ability to extract resources from the
planet that are not replenishing
themselves which is what the Industrial
Revolution was rate mining farming
fishing logging etc the ability to take
some kind of resource reserves that took
hundreds of millions or billions of
years to develop and to be able to
extract them at a radically fast pace
and obviously much faster than they can
renew and then the population is growing
on that savings account until you hit
the ends of the savings account and then
there's real problems not only have we
been growing in population but we've
been growing in resource consumption per
capita when we think about running an
economy
it requires year-over-year growth
requires it so that kind of exponential
growth economy and attached to a linear
materials economy just doesn't work
ongoing Leon
my planet right it only would work
ongoingly on an infinite line field turn
Allah and so that is a fundamentally
self terminating system it makes plenty
of sense that when there was just so
much low-hanging fruit in terms of coal
and oil and fish and trees and etc that
we would do this exponential boom kind
of thing it's just that's not viable
anymore thanks for watching this video
if you liked it and you want more of it
consider subscribing and going to future
thinkers org if you want to listen to
the full episode click the link in the
description don't forget to comment rate
subscribe if you want to support the
show consider becoming a patron go to
patreon.com/scishow machine